Xin JIN

M3052, 5/F, Run Run Shaw Creative Media Centre, 18 Tat Hong Avenue, Kowloon Tong, Hong Kong

E-mail: xin.jin@cityu.edu.hk, Tel: (+852)57499397

Profile

The research I have done before including popular culture, media and gender, and ideology analysis. Now I focus on computational social science, political communication, and data mining-processing-visualization. Meanwhile, I am also interested in creative media and proficient in many types of video producing, especially in documentary, creative microfilm, interview and news comment. I have a strong desire to try new things in both research and practice.

Education

City University of Hong Kong	Hong Kong, China
M.A. in Communication and New Media-Media Data Analytics Stream	2018-Present

Fudan University	Shanghai, China
F.I.S.T. Summer School in Quantitative Communication Research Method	Jul 2018

Shanghai Jiao Tong University	Shanghai, China
Communication Elite Seminar in New Media and Big Data	Jul 2017

Jinan University & Northwestern University & BBC	Guangzhou, Guangdong, China
Workshop for Media Leaders	Jul 2015

Central South University	Changsha, Hunan, China
B.A. (with honors) in Radio and Television	2014-2018

Research

Project

The Mechanism of How Self-media Influences People's Cognition and Code of Conduct

(National-level S.R.T.P. Fund, Project#201610533241, 10,000 CNY)

Mar 2017

Responsibility

Leader

Research method and questionnaire designing, ideology and myth analysis

Achievement

Award for Excellent Academic Innovation Project Award for Excellent Academic Innovation Paper

Analysis of Web Texts of Social Hot Events

Jun 2017

(Provincial Social Science Foundation of China)

Participant of instructor's project (Dr. Huang) Leader of 'Wei Zexi event' text analysis group Analysis of dominant reading

Xin JIN

Study of Violent Narration in Current Mass Culture

Aug 2017

(Provincial Social Science Foundation of China)

Participant of instructor's project (Dr. Huang) Semiotic analysis of language violence, behavior violence and environment violence of 10 popular movies

• Research Experience

Research Assistant

(Project#9042463, Prof. Fen Lin, Dept Media & Communication, City U) Jan 2019-Present

The Rank of School / Department in Communication and Media Study Around the World

(Research Intern, Prof. Jonathan J.H. Zhu, Web Mining Lab, City U) Oct 2018-Present

New Bottle of New Wine or Old Bottle of New Wine: The Comparison of Computational Communication Research and Non-computational Communication Research

Nov 2018
(Research Intern, Web Mining Lab, Prof. Jonathan J.H. Zhu)

Conference

Jin, X., Ye, Q. Y. (05/01/2019). Impact of Different Social Media Context on Attitude Polarization of Hot Topic Online. *The 1st CUC Ph.D Students Academic Forum on New Media*, Communication University of China, Beijing, China.

Professional Achievement

You Young New Media Studio

Mar 2018

(National-level S.E.T.P. Fund, Project#201810533586, 10,000 CNY)

Responsibility

Leader & Founder

Achievement

Award for Excellent Entrepreneurship Practice Project

Second Award in 'Shenghua Cup' Competition of Science and Technology (Cultural and Creative Industry Track)

Film Works

National College Students' Sports Micro Film Contest

Top 10 prize-Zero Distance with Rio Olympic Champions

National Cross-strait College Students Visual Works Exhibition

1st prize-Days of Being Sorrowful (Cantonese)

National Medical Health Science Micro Video Contest

Grand prize-How to Dress Correctly for Newborns

Hunan Radio & Television Program Contest, Hunan Satellite TV

3rd prize-Changsha on the Fingertip

Xin JIN

The 5th Hunan College Student Art Exhibition

3rd prize-Talk to Myself (Cantonese)

Hunan TV & Radio College Association TV Program Contest

1st prize-Seniors Speaking from the Bottom of the Heart 2nd prize-Long Drum from the Distant Mountain 3rd prize-the Battle in Millimeters (Hand-made Contest of Clinical Medical Students)

Honors and Awards

Distinction Bachelor Graduate Award, Central South University	Jun 2018
National Scholarship, Ministry of Education of P.R.C	Nov 2017
Excellent Academic Innovation Individual, Office of Innovation of CSU	May 2017
Second-class Scholarship, Central South University	Nov 2015, Nov 2016

Skills

SPSS-Skilled, Python-Fundamental, Power Point-Proficient, Word-Proficient Excel-Skilled, Adobe Premiere-Professional

Links

Personal Website https://xjincomm.wixsite.com/xjin

CityU Staff Profile Page http://www6.cityu.edu.hk/stfprofile/xin.jin.htm

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/xjin613

You Young Creative Media Studio

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCoKxYZjMWNfthjj211gJSKQ